Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection AIA 004
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection
1811-2008 (bulk 1964-2005)
AIA 004
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
47.0 linear feet (7 boxes; 161 oversize boxes)
This collection contains major runs of several prominent Irish-American newspapers and periodicals. Titles held include Irish Echo, Irish Edition, Irish People, An Phoblacht / Republican News, Irish Voice, Irish World, An Gael (published by the Irish Arts Center, New York), Irish America, The Nation and The World of Hibernia.
Archives of Irish America.
Provenance
The materials in this collection were collected by Archives staff or donated by various sources, including the Consulate General of Ireland, The Irish Bookshop, Cherry Lane Productions, Marion Casey, Linda Dowling Almeida, and Cormac K.H. O’Malley beginning in 1996. The 19th century papers were donated by Sean Prendiville.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. Some papers are fragile and must be handled with care, especially An Goadhal.
Historical/Biographical Note
The materials in this collection were collected by Archives staff or donated by various sources, including the Consulate General of Ireland, The Irish Bookshop, Cherry Lane Productions, Marion Casey, Linda Dowling Almeida, and Cormac K. H. O’Malley beginning in 1996. The Nation and Spirit of Freedom were included in donations from Sean Prendiville and George Harrison. The nineteenth century papers were donated by Sean Prendiville.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of runs of several major Irish-American newspapers and periodicals, including the Advocate (1968-1989), Irish People (1972-2004), An Phoblacht / Republican News the official newspaper of Sinn Fein (1984-2005), Irish Voice (1987-2003), and the Irish Echo (1964-2003). Also included are issues of other papers such as Irish World, Irish Herald and regional papers like the Boston Irish News, Irish American Press out of Southern California, and The Tablet from Queens and Brooklyn, New York. A few 19th-century papers are also found in the collection notably, the Irish Citizen (1871-1897), Green Banner (1836), the Shamrock(1811). The Phoenix out of New York (1859-1861) is included in microfilm format only.
Subseries were created for newspaper titles with multiple years, including The Advocate, An Phoblacht / Republican News, Irish Echo, Irish People and Irish Voice.
Of note in the publications series are The Nation, published by the Irish American Defense Fund and Spirit of Freedom, an Irish-American publication in support of the Republicans in Northern Ireland. Also of interest is a significant run of Irish America, a magazine focusing on Irish in America and famous Americans of Irish heritage, as well as Ireland of the Welcomes, a publication put out by the Ireland Tourist Board and an Irish- language serial, An Gadohal, a "bi-lingual magazine devoted to the promotion of the "Language Literature, Music and Art of Ireland" dating from the late 1800s to 1902.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
George Harrison Papers AIA 009
Irish Republicanism Collection AIA 022
Cormac K.H. O'Malley Papers AIA 019
Patrick Daughton Collection AIA 055
Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA 060
Arrangement
The materials are organized alphabetically by title and chronologically within each title.
The collection is arranged into two series: Newspapers and Periodicals. Within the newspapers are several subseries for newspapers with multiple years, including The Advocate, An Phoblacht / Republican News, Irish Echo, Irish People and Irish Voice.
I. Newspapers, 1836-2008
II. Other Publications, 1881-2008
Irish America.; Irish echo (Boston, Mass.: 1981).; Irish echo.; Irish voice (New York, N.Y.) .; Irish world.; Nation, The.; Spirit of Freedom.; The Irish people.; World of Hibernia.; Chicago (Ill.); England.; Irish Americans |v Periodicals.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |v Periodicals.; Irish Americans |z Pennsylvania |z Philadelphia |v Newspapers.; Irish Americans--Massachusetts--Boston--Newspapers.; Irish Americans--New York (State)-–Newspapers.; Irish Americans--Newspapers.; Journals (periodicals); Magazines (Periodicals); Newspapers.; Periodicals.; San Francisco (Calif.)
- I: Newspapers, 1836-2008
  - The Advocate, 1968-1989
    - Nov 2, 1968, Oct 23, 1971, Jan 26, 1974, Mar 19, 1977, Jan 5 1980 - Dec 27, 1980, Jan 30, 1981 - Apr 11, 1981 [Vol. 87, Nos. 4464-4515 (Missing 4467, 4472, 4477, 4503, 4504) Vol. 88, Nos. 4517-4530 (Missing 4516)], Nov 1968-Apr 1981 (Box 1)
    - Apr 18, 1981 – Dec 26, 1981, Jan 2, 1982 – Sep 25, 1982 [Vol. 88, Nos. 4531-4567, Vol. 89, Nos. 4568-4606 (Missing 4591)], 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Oct 2, 1982 – Dec 25, 1982; Jan 1, 1983 – Dec 31, 1983 [Vol. 89, Nos. 4607-4619, Vol. 89, Nos. 4620-4672, (Missing 4635,4636,4642,4665,4666)], 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Jan 7, 1984 – Dec 29, 1984 [Vol. 91, Nos. 4673-4724 (Missing 4694, 4699, 4700, 4702, 4703, 4705, 4708, 4709, 4719)] (Box 4)
    - Jan 5, 1985 – Dec 21, 1985; Jan 4, 1986 – Jun 28, 1986 [Vol. 92, Nos. 4725-4775 (Missing 4741, 4744, 4749, 4752, 4760, 4761, 4765-4767, 4772) Vol. 93, Nos. 4777-4802] (Box 5)
    - The Advocate: Jul 5, 1986 – Dec 27, 1986; Jan 3, 1987 – Sep 26, 1987 [Vol. 93, Nos. 4803-4828 (Missing 4804, 4807, 4809, 4810, 4815, 4822), Vol. 94, Nos. 4829-4867 (Missing 4849)], 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - Oct 3, 1987 – Dec 26, 1987; Jan 2, 1988 – Dec 24, 1988; Jan 7, 1989 – Apr 22, 1989 [Vol. 94, Nos. 4858-4880, Vol. 95, Nos. 4881-4932 (Missing 4894) Vol. 95/96, Nos. 4934-4949 (Missing 4946)], 1987-1989 (Box 7)
  - American Record: Vol. 1, No. 1; Vol. 11 Mar 17, 1975; May – Jun, 1975; Jul 4, 1975 (Box 144)
  - An Phoblacht / Republican News (Dublin) [For a complete listing of year, volume and number please see Archivist.], 1984-2005
    - March 1984, 1989-June 1994 (with gaps), 1984-1994 (Box 169)
    - July 1994-December 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 170)
    - 1996-June 1997, 1996-Jun 1997 (Box 171)
    - July 1997 - 1998, Jul 1997-1998 (Box 172)
    - 1999-2000 (with gaps) (Box 173)
    - 2001-2005 (with gaps) (Box 174)
  - The Boston Irish News, 1986–1990 (Box 146)
  - Catholic New York: Vol. 15, No. 26, Mar 1996 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Connection: Vol. 1, No. 3, Dec 1991, Jan 1992 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Mirror / An Scathan: Vol. 1, Nos. 1, 8, Vol. 3, No. 12, Mar 1995–Feb 1998 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Weekly, Mar 1872–Sep 1873 (Box 147)
  - Clan-na-Gael Journal (Philadelphia) Aug 5, 1895; Jun 27, 1915, 1895-1915 (Box 158)
    Provenance
    Gift of Sean Prendiville
  - Fenian News, Vol. 2 and 3, 1930-1931 (Box 158)
  - Florida Irish – American, Nov 1990 (Box 144)
  - Fortnight, Nov 1971–Dec 1971 (Box 144)
  - Gael, Jul 1998 (Box 144)
  - Globe and Emerald (New York) Vol. 2, No. 11, 1825 (Box 149)
  - Green Banner, 1836 (Box 148)
  - Ireland Digest (Dublin), May 1986 (Box 145)
  - Irish American Post, Apr 1992–Apr 2001 (Box 149)
  - Irish American Press (Southern CA), Jul 1989–Nov 1991 (Box 144)
  - Irish American Review (St. Louis, MO), Mar 1987 (Box 144)
  - Irish Arts Center Newsletter, Oct 1992–Oct 1994 (Box 144)
  - Irish Citizen, Jul 1871–Oct 1897 (Box 150)
  - Irish Democrat (London), Jan 1984–Jul 1988 (Box 145)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1964-2008
    - Nov 28, 1964; 1966 Easter Rising 50th Anniversary Supplement; Dec 13, 1969; Jul 24, 1971; Apr 22, 1972; Feb 24, 1973, 1964-1973 (Box 8)
    - Mar 3-Dec 29, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Jan 5-Dec 28, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Jan 24-Sep 13, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Sep 20-Dec 27, 1975; Jan 10-Sep 25, 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
    - Oct 20-Dec 25, 1976; Jan 1-Jun 25, 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - Jul 2-Oct 2, 1977; Jan 14-Dec 30, 1978; Jan 13-Mar 31, 1979, 1977-1979 (Box 14)
    - Apr 7-Nov 24, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Jan 5-Apr 26, 1980 (Box 16)
    - May 3-Oct 18, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Oct 25-Dec 27, 1980; Jan 3-Apr 4, 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 18)
    - Sep 4-Dec 25, 1982; Jan 1-Apr 30, 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - May 7-Dec 31, 1983 (Box 20)
    - Jan 7-Aug 25, 1984 (Box 21)
    - Sep 1-Dec 29, 1984; Jan 5-Mar 16, 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 22)
    - Mar 22-Oct 26, 1985 (Box 23)
    - Nov 2-Dec 25, 1985; Jan 4-May 24, 1986, 1985-1986 (Box 24)
    - May 31-Dec 27, 1986 (Box 25)
    - Jan 3-Jul 18, 1987 (Box 26)
    - Jul 25-Dec 26, 1987 (Box 27)
    - Jan 2-May 5, 1988 (Box 28)
    - May 21-Sep 17, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Sep 24-Dec 31, 1988; Jan 7-Mar 4, 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 30)
    - Mar 11-Jul 1, 1989 (Box 31)
    - Jul 8-Dec 30, 1989 (Box 32)
    - Jan 13-May 29, 1990 (Box 33)
    - May 30-Oct 16, 1990 (Box 34)
    - Oct 25, 1990-Mar 26, 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 35)
    - Mar 27-Nov 12, 1991 (Box 36)
    - Nov 13-Dec 31, 1991; Jan 1-May 26, 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 37)
    - Jun 2-Dec 29, 1992 (Box 38)
    - Dec 30, 1992-Jun 8, 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 39)
    - Jun 9-Oct 26, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Oct 27, 1993-Mar 8, 1994, 1993-1994 (Box 41)
    - Mar 9-May 15, 1994 (Box 42)
    - May 18-Sep 27, 1994 (Box 43)
    - Sep 28, 1994-Jan 3, 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 44)
    - Jan 4-Mar 15, 1995 (Box 45)
    - Mar 22-Jun 28, 1995 (Box 46)
    - Jul 5-Sep 20, 1995 (Box 47)
    - Oct 4-Dec 27, 1995 (Box 48)
    - Jan 3-May 1, 1996 (Box 49)
    - May 8-Aug 14, 1996 (Box 50)
    - Aug 21-Dec 25, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Jan 8-May 17, 1997 (Box 52)
    - May 28-Oct 28, 1997 (Box 53)
    - Oct 29-Dec 24, 1997; Jan 1-Mar 24, 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 54)
    - Mar 25-Aug 11, 1998 (Box 55)
    - Aug 12-Dec 23, 1998 (Box 56)
    - Jan 6-Jun 1, 1999 (Box 57)
    - Jun 2-Dec 28, 1999 (Box 58)
    - Dec 29, 1999-May 17, 2000, 1999-2000 (Box 59)
    - May 24-Oct 4, 2000 (Box 60)
    - Oct 11-Dec 27, 2000; Jan 3-Mar 7, 2001, 2000-2001 (Box 61)
    - Mar 14-Jul 18, 2001 (Box 62)
    - Jul 25-Dec 26, 2001 (Box 63)
    - Jan 9-May 15, 2002 (Box 64)
    - May 22-Oct 9, 2002 (Box 65)
    - Oct 16-Dec 25, 2002; Jan 8-Feb 25, 2003, 2002-2003 (Box 66)
    - Feb 26-Jul 22, 2003 (Box 67)
    - Jul 23-Dec 9, 2003 (Box 68A)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 68B)
    - 2007 (Box 68C)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 68D)
  - Irish Echo Boston Edition: Jan 25, 1986 – Dec 27, 1986 (Box 69)
  - Irish Echo Boston Edition: Jan 3, 1987 – Aug 29, 1987; May 7, 1988 – May 14, 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 70)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): Jan. – Dec. 1984, Jan. – Dec. 1985, Feb. – July 1986, June – Dec. 1989, Jan, May 1990, Jan. 1991 [Vol. 4, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 8,9,11), Vol. 5, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 9,10), Vol. 6 Nos. 2-7 (Missing 1,4,6), Vol. 9, Nos. 6-12 (Missing 1-5), Vol. 10, Nos. 1,5, Vol. 11, No. 1], Jan 1984-Jan 2000, 2007-2008 (Box 71)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): April, June, Nov. 1993, Jan. – Dec. 1994, Jan. – Dec. 1995, Jan. – Dec. 1996 [Vol. 13, Nos. 4,6,11, Vol. 14, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 2,3,7,9), Vol. 15, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 6,11), Vol. 16, Nos. 1-12, (Missing 2,4,10)], 1994-1996 (Box 72)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): Jan. – Dec. 1997, Feb. – Dec. 1998, Jan. – Dec. 1999, Jan. 2000 [Vol. 17, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 5,11), Vol. 18, Nos. 2-12 (Missing 1,5,9), Marked Vol. 18, Nos. 12, 2-12, Vol. 20, No. 1], 1997-2000 (Bin 73)
  - The Irish Emigrant, 1994–2001, 2006, 2008 (Box 151)
  - Irish Eyes, Jan 1995, Mar 1995 (Box 145)
  - Irish Herald (San Francisco, CA), Jan 1974–Jul 2000 (Box 152)
  - The Irish Herald, 2001–2003 (Box 153)
  - The Irish Literary Supplement (Selden, NY), 1983-1992, 1994-2004 (Box 154)
  - Irishman (San Francisco, CA), Dec 1984–Mar 1989 (Box 145)
  - Irish People (includes Supplement of Nov. 23, 1867), Jan 1868–May 1876 (Box 155)
  - Irish People (New York), 1972-2004
    - Jul-Dec 1972; Jan-Mar, 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 74)
    - Mar 31-Dec 29, 1973 (Box 75)
    - Jan 5-Aug 10, 1974 (Box 76)
    - Aug 17-Dec 28, 1974; Jan 4-Oct 18, 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 77)
    - Jan 24-Dec 18, 1976; Jan 1-Jul 16, 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 78)
    - Jul 23-Dec 24, 1977; Jan 7-Apr 8, 1978, 1977-1978 (Box 79)
    - Apr 15-Dec 23, 1978; Jan 6-Mar 17, 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 80)
    - Mar 24-Dec 22, 1979 (Box 81)
    - Jan 12-Oct 18, 1980 (Box 82)
    - Oct 25-Dec 20, 1980; Jan 1-Sep 18, 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 83)
    - Sept-Dec 1981; Jan 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 84)
    - Feb-Jun 1982 (Box 85)
    - Jul-Dec 1982 (Box 86)
    - Jan-Jun 1983 (Box 87)
    - Jul-Dec, 1983 (Box 88)
    - Jan-Dec, 1984 (Box 89)
    - Jan-May, 1985 (Box 90)
    - Jun-Dec, 1985 (Box 91)
    - Jan-Mar, 1986 (Box 92)
    - Apr-Jul, 1986 (Box 93)
    - Aug-Dec, 1986 (Box 94)
    - Feb-Oct, 1987 (with gaps); Apr 23, 1988; June 30, 1990; Dec 15, 1990, 1987-1990 (Box 95)
    - Jan-Dec 1991 (Box 96)
    - May-Dec, 1992 (Box 97)
    - Jan-Dec, 1993 (Box 98)
    - Jan-Jun, 1994 (Box 99)
    - Jul-Dec, 1994 (Box 100)
    - Oct 7, 1995; Oct 5, 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 101)
    - Jan-May, 1997 (Box 102)
    - Jun-Dec, 1997 (Box 103)
    - Jan-Apr, 1998 (Box 104)
    - May-Aug, 1998 (Box 105)
    - Sep-Dec, 1998 (Box 106)
    - Jan-Apr, 2001 (Box 107)
    - May-Jul, 2001 (Box 108)
    - Aug-Dec, 2001 (Box 109)
    - Jan-Apr, 2002 (Box 110)
    - May-Aug, 2002 (Box 111)
    - Sep-Dec, 2002 (Box 112)
    - Jan-Jul 12, 2003 (Box 113)
    - Jul 19-Dec 2003 (Box 114)
    - Feb-Aug, 2004 (Box 115)
  - Irish Post: The Voice of the Irish in Britain (London), Jun 1985–Sept 1987 (Box 145)
  - Irish Rebel (Friends of Irish Freedom, Boston), Vol 1, No. 1, Nov 1969 (Box 149)
  - Irish Voice (New York), 1987-2008
    - Dec 5, 1987 - Dec 26, 1987: Vol. 1, Nos. 1-4/ Jan 2, 1988 - May 21, 1988: Vol. 2, Nos. 1-21, 1987-1988 (Box 116)
    - May 28, 1988 - Dec 24 - 31, 1988: Vol. 2, Nos. 22-52 (missing 48) (Box 117)
    - Jan 7, 1989 - Jun 3, 1989: Vol. 3, Nos. 1-22 (Box 118)
    - Jun 10, 1989 - Dec 23-30, 1989: Vol. 3, Nos. 23-51 (missing 28) (Box 119)
    - Jan 6, 1990 - May 19, 1990: Vol. 4, Nos. 1-20 (Box 120)
    - May 26, 1990 - Oct 13, 1990: Vol. 4, Nos. 21-41 (Box 121)
    - Oct 20, 1990 - Dec 22-29, 1990: Vol. 4, Nos. 42-51/ Jan 5, 1991 - Mar 9, 1991: Vol. 5., Nos. 1-10, 1990-1991 (Box 122)
    - Mar. 16-May 26, 1991: Vol. 5, Nos. 11-23 (Box 123)
    - Jun 1, 1991 - Oct 8, 1991: Vol. 5, Nos. 24-40 (Box 124)
    - Oct 15, 1991 - Dec 24-31, 1991: Vol. 5, Nos. 41-51 (Box 125)
    - Jan 7, 1992 -Jul 21, 1992: Vol. 6, Nos. 1-29 (Box 126)
    - Jul 28, 1992 - Dec 22, 1992: Vol 6., Nos. 30-52 (Box 127)
    - Dec 29, 1992 - May 25, 1993: Vol. 7, Nos. 1-21, 1992-1993 (Box 128)
    - Jun 1, 1993 - Dec 21, 1993: Vol. 7, Nos. 22-51 (missing 52) (Box 129)
    - Dec 23, 1993 - Aug 9, 1994: Vol. 8, Nos. 1-32, 1993-1994 (Box 130)
    - Aug 17, 1994 - Jan 3, 1995: Vol. 8, Nos. 34-52/ Jan 3, 1995 - Mar 14, 1995: Vol. 9, Nos. 1-11, 1994-1995 (Box 131)
    - Mar 15, 1995 - Jan 2, 1996: Vol. 9, Nos. 12-52 (missing 14, 15, 23, 25, 39), 1995-1996 (Box 132)
    - Dec 20, 1995 - Jul 30, 1996: Vol. 10, Nos. 1-31, 1995-1996 (Box 133)
    - Jul 31 - Dec 30, 1996: Vol. 10, Nos. 32-53 (Box 134)
    - Dec 31, 1996 - Jul 16, 1997: Vol. 11, Nos. 1-36 (missing 14, 31, 32), 1996-1997 (Box 135)
    - Jul 23, 1997 - Dec 30, 1997: Vol. 11, Nos. 38-52 (missing 37, 41, 43, 46) (Box 136)
    - Dec 31, 1997- Jul 22, 1998: Vol. 12, Nos. 1-30, 1997-1998 (Box 137)
    - Jul 29, 1998 - Dec 23, 1998: Vol. 12, Nos. 31-52 (missing 50)/ Jan 6, 1999 - Feb 10, 1999: Vol. 13, Nos. 1-7 (missing 2), 1998-1999 (Box 138)
    - Feb 24, 1999 - Dec 22, 1999: Vol. 13, Nos. 9-52 (missing 8, 15, 19, 31-34, 36-38, 40, 41, 46, 48) (Box 139)
    - May 10, Sept. 13, Sept. 27, Oct. 4, 2000: Vol. 14, Nos. 20, 38, 40, 41/ Jul. 11, Jul. 25, Aug. 15, Aug. 22, 2001: Vol. 15, Nos. 29, 30, 32, 34, 35/ Feb. 13, Mar. 6, Mar. 13, Mar. 27, Apr. 10, Apr. 17, Apr. 21, May 1, 2002: Vol. 16, Nos. 8, 10-12, 14-19/ Sept. 10, Oct. 8, Oct. 15, Nov. 19, 2003: Vol. 17, Nos. 37, 41, 42, 47, 2000-2003 (Box 140)
    - Nov 2006 - Jul 2007, 2006-2007 (Box 167)
    - Jul 2007- Mar 2008, 2007-2008 (Box 168)
  - Irish World: Oct 23, 1971; Feb 2, 1974 - Mar 30, 1974, May 17, 1975; Feb 10, 1979; Jan 5, 1980 – Dec 20, 1980,; Jan 10, 1981 – Mar 28, 1981 [Vol. 102, No. 5288, Vol. 104, Nos. 5407 – 5409, 5413-5415, Vol. 105, No. 5494, Vol. 109, No. 5689, Vol. 110, Nos. 5732-5782 (Missing 5741,5754), Vol. 111, Nos. 5785-5796 (Missing 5794)], 1971-1981 (Box 141)
  - Irish World: Apr 4, 1981 – Dec 26, 1981; Jan 2, 1982 – Dec 25, 1982 [Vol. 111, Nos. 5797-5837 (Missing 5801-5803,5814,5823), Vol. 112, Nos. 5838-5889 (Missing 5879)], 1981-1982 (Box 142)
  - Irish World: Jan 1, 1983 – Dec 24, 1983; Jan 7, 1984 – Nov 17, 1984 [Vol. 113, Nos. 5890-5941 (Missing 5908,5937), Vol. 114, Nos. 5932-5985 (Missing 5962,5968,5973-5975,5983)], 1983-1984 (Box 143)
  - National Hibernian Digest, Jan 1974–May 1984 (Box 156)
  - The Phoenix (New York) [Microfilm], 1859–1861 (Box 157)
  - Plain Dealer "PD Action Tab", Mar 1973 (Box 145)
  - San Francisco Gael, Feb 1993–Mar 1994 (Box 145)
  - Saoirse (Irish Freedom)(Dublin), May-Oct 1972, May 1987–Oct 1998 (Box 145)
    1972 editions Gift of Sean Prendiville
  - Shamrock News, Mar 1976 (Box 145)
  - Shamrock Newspaper (NY), 1811 (Box 158)
  - South Boston On-Line Print Edition, Jul 2001 (Box 145)
  - Sovereign Nation (Dublin), Oct 1998, Aug 2001 (Box 145)
  - Tablet (Queens and Brooklyn, NY), Mar 1996 (Box 145)
  - Tom Mannion Travel Supplement, Feb 1985 (Box 145)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), 1955–1961 (Box 149)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), Aug 1971-May 1972 (Box 149)
- II: Periodicals, 1881-2008
  - Ais Eiri: The Magazine of Irish-America, 1979-1981 (Box 160, Folder 1A)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1963-1964, 1966-1968, 1970 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1971-1976 (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1977-1979 (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - American Gael, 1992-1999 (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1993-1997 (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 160, Folder 5A)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, Feb 2000-Jul 2000 (Box 160, Folder 5B)
  - American Journal of Gaelic Culture (Chicago), 1996-1997 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soulis, Inc. - Newsletter - Litir Nuacht, 1971-1977 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - Sword of Light,The Irish American Review, 1974 (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc.- Ais-Eiri The Magazine of Irish America, Win 1979-Spr 1982 (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1982-1983 (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1984-1985 (Box 160, Folder 10)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1986 (Box 160, Folder 11)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1987 (Box 160, Folder 12)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1990-1992 (Box 160, Folder 13)
  - An Doras, 1996-1998 (Box 160, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1881, 1886-1889 (Box 166, Folder 10)
  - An Gaodhal, 1890 (Box 166, Folder 11)
  - An Gaodhal, 1891, 1893-1894 (Box 166, Folder 12)
  - An Gaodhal, 1896 (Box 166, Folder 13)
  - An Gaodhal, 1897-1899 (Box 166, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1900-1902 (Box 166, Folder 15)
  - Bard, The, 1996-1999 (Box 160, Folder 15)
  - Beyond Ben Bulben (Australia), 1996-1997 (Box 160, Folder 16)
  - Bonded Shores, 1994-2000 (Box 160, Folder 17)
  - The Bridge: An Droichead, 1986-1987 (Box 160, Folder 18)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1977-1981 (Box 160, Folder 19)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1982-2008 (Box 160, Folder 20)
  - Carn: A Link Between Celtic Nations, 1974-1978 (Box 160, Folder 21)
  - Celtic News Service, 1975-1977, 1992-1996 (Box 160, Folder 22)
  - Celtic Renewal, 1995 (Box 160, Folder 23)
  - Cois na Farraige, 1984 (Box 160, Folder 24)
  - Desert Shamrock, 1994 (Box 160, Folder 25)
  - Ducas, 1971-1981 with gaps (Box 161, Folder 26)
  - Ducas, 1985-2002 (Box 161, Folder 27)
  - Eire Ireland, 1963-1968 (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Eire Ireland, 1969-1973 (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Everyman, 1994-1995 (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Gaelic Journal, 1900 (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Gander, 1993-1997 (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Gander, 1998-1999 (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - Gander, 1999-2001, 2002, 2004 (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Harp: "Voice of the Irish Impression", Jun 1988 (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Here's Me Bus!, 1995-1996 (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Holy Cross Quarterl y: The Irish Issue, Vol. 6, Nos. 1-4. College of the Holy Cross, Worcester, MA., 1974 (Box 161, Folder 9A)
  - Hornpipe: Irish Dance, Music and Culture in North America, 1999 (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Inside Ireland, 1984, 1999 (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, Mar 1966-Mar 1978 (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1984 (Box 161, Folder 13)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1985 (Box 161, Folder 14)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1986 (Box 161, Folder 15)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1987 (Box 161, Folder 16)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1988 (Box 161, Folder 17)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1989 (Box 161, Folder 18)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1990 (Box 161, Folder 19)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1991 (Box 162, Folder 20)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1992 (Box 162, Folder 21)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1993 (Box 162, Folder 22)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1994 (Box 162, Folder 23)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1995 (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1996 (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1997-1998 (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1999 (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 2000-2001 (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, 1985, undated (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - Irish America, Jan 1986-Apr 1986 (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Irish America, May 1986-Dec 1986 (Box 162, Folder 8)
  - Irish America, 1987 (Box 162, Folder 9)
  - Irish America, 1988 (Box 162, Folder 10)
  - Irish America, 1989 (Box 162, Folder 11)
  - Irish America, 1990 (Box 162, Folder 12)
  - Irish America, 1991 (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Irish America, 1992 (Box 163, Folder 14)
  - Irish America, 1993 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Irish America, Jan 1994-Jun 1994 (Box 163, Folder 2)
  - Irish America, Jan 1994-Aug 1994 (Box 163, Folder 3)
  - Irish America, Jan 1995-Aug 1995 (Box 163, Folder 4)
  - Irish America, Sep 1995-Dec 1995 (Box 163, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, Jan 1996-Apr 1996 (Box 163, Folder 6)
  - Irish America, May 1996-Dec 1996 (Box 163, Folder 7)
  - Irish America, 1997 (Box 163, Folder 8)
  - Irish America, Mar 1998-Aug 1998 (Box 163, Folder 9)
  - Irish America, Sep 1998-Dec 1998 (Box 163, Folder 10)
  - Irish America, Feb 1999-Jul 1999 (Box 163, Folder 11)
  - Irish America, Aug 1999-Nov 1999 (Box 163, Folder 12)
  - Irish America, Jan 2000-Mar 2000 (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Irish America, May 2000 (Box 163, Folder 14)
  - Irish America, Aug 2000-Nov 2000 (Box 163, Folder 15)
  - Irish America, Dec 2000-May 2001 (Box 164, Folder 16)
  - Irish America, Jun 2001-Nov 2001 (Box 164, Folder 17)
  - Irish America, Feb 2002-Nov 2002 (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Irish America, Jan 2003-Nov 2003 (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - Irish America, Jan 2004-May 2004 (Box 164, Folder 3)
  - Irish America, Jun 2004-Sep 2004 (Box 164, Folder 4)
  - Irish America, Jan 2005-Jul 2005 (Box 164, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, Dec 2010-Jan 2011 (Box 164, Folder 5A)
  - Irish American Post Magazine, 1997 (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - Irish American Voice, 1984 (Box 164, Folder 7)
  - Irish American Voice, 1985 (Box 164, Folder 8)
  - Irish American Voice, 1986 (Box 164, Folder 9)
  - Irish American Voice, 1987 (Box 164, Folder 10)
  - Irish at Home and Abroad, 1993-1995 (Box 164, Folder 11)
  - Irish Dancer, 1998 (Box 164, Folder 12)
  - IE: A Supplement to the Irish Echo, 1996-1998 (Box 164, Folder 13)
  - Irish People (Chicago) Vol. 1, nos. 5-6, 8-12; Vol 2. nos. 5,9,11; Vol 3. no. 1 (also available on microfilm in Tamiment), Oct 1923-Jan 1933 with gaps (Box 164, Folder 14)
  - Irish Voice Magazine, 1954 (Box 164, Folder 15)
  - Irish Volunteer, 1991, 2000 (Box 164, Folder 16)